

Peer Christensen

Data Scientist

6+ years experience quantifying and predicting patterns in various types of data. Truly passionate about many core aspects of data science including data wrangling, visualisation, machine learning, text mining and programming. I am constantly improving my skillset while unraveling and communicating insights from complex data.

Copenhagen, Denmark

in dk.linkedin.com/in/peer-christensen-datascientist

+45 5357 1604

peerchristensen.netlify.com

github.com/PeerChristensen

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

Saxo.com

09/2019 - Present Copenhagen

Main Tasks

- Upgrading all machine learning projects, models and techniques
- Developing robust pipelines using Docker and Azure cloud
- Developing NLP-based recommendations strategies and web apps

Data Scientist

Geomatic

01/2019 - 07/2019 Copenhagen

Main tasks

- Automating workflows for data acquisition, blending and enrichment
- Developing core functionality of a self-service app for churn prediction in R

EDUCATION

PhD student in Linguistics Lund University

2014 - Present Lund, SE

Selected PhD courses

- Machine learning in R
- Advanced statistical methods in R
- Text analytics in Python
- Python for developing experiments

MA Cognitive Science

Aarhus University

2010 - 2013 Aarhus

BA Linguistics
 Aarhus University

2006 - 2010 Aarhus and Nijmegen, NL

TOOLS & TECHNICAL SKILLS

R Python SQL Azure Machine learning NLP
Tableau Shiny H2O

RECENT DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

Creating Shiny web app explaining predictions and performance of classification models to stakeholders

Text mining 10.000+ ebooks: topic modelling, stylometry, sentiment analysis, word2vec etc.

Predicting and clustering best-selling novels to add a new layer to the business

Insourcing personalized product recommendations via ML saving 17.000DKK in monthly fees

Scraping and extracting valuable insights from customer reviews

PUBLICATIONS

Typical pain experience but underestimation of others' pain: Emotion perception in self and others in autism spectrum disorder. Autism, 2017

Environmental constraints shaping constituent order in emerging communication systems. Cognition. 2016

Brains striving for coherence: Long-term cumulative plot formation in the default mode network. NeuroImage, 2015

Cross-modal integration of affective facial expression and vocal prosody: an EEG study. SALC, 2012

LANGUAGES

English				
Danish				
French				0
Swedish				0
Italian		0	0	0